jumpforward.com 2013-11-20

# Privacy Statement – College Recruiting and Compliance Software

## Privacy Statement

### **Privacy Policy**

This document governs the privacy policy of our Website. Our Privacy Policy is considered a part of our Legal Terms. Any capitalized terms not defined herein have the same meaning as defined elsewhere in our Legal Terms. Our Privacy Policy was last updated on July 17, 2013.  
Definitions  
“Non-Personal Information” is information that is in no way personally identifiable and that is obtained automatically through your simple use of our Website with a web browser.  
“Personally Identifiable Information” is non-public information that is personally identifiable and obtained in connection with providing a product or service to you. It may include information such as your name, address, phone number, and other related information you provide to us. 

Our Commitment to Your Privacy  
This Privacy Policy tells you what Personally Identifiable Information we may collect from you, how we may share this information, and how you can limit our sharing of your information.

JumpForward is committed to the security and privacy of all our clients. We take your privacy seriously, and we will work with you to ensure that you can use our Website, as well as purchase our products and services in a safe and secure online environment.

JumpForward and its affiliates are committed to respecting your privacy and recognize the need for appropriate protection and management of your Personally Identifiable Information you share with us.

As a part of our commitment to your privacy, we support the guidelines and practices adopted by the Direct Marketing Association Privacy Promise to American consumers. Accordingly, we have agreed to (1) provide you with notice of their ability to opt out of information exchanges with other marketers; (2) honor your request not to have their information transferred to others for marketing purposes; and (3) accept and honor your request not to receive solicitations from any of our affiliates.

Links to Other Websites  
Our Website may contain links to other websites that are not under our control. These websites may have their own policies regarding privacy. We have no control of or responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. You access such linked Websites at your own risk. These websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should check the privacy policies, if any, of those individual websites to see how the operators of those third-party websites will utilize your personal information. In addition, these websites may contain a link to Websites of our affiliates. The websites of our affiliates are not subject to this Privacy Policy, and you should check their individual privacy policies to see how the operators of such websites will utilize your personal information.

What Information We May Collect  
Generally, you can visit our Website and use our website without providing or revealing any Personally Identifiable Information. We receive and store certain types of Non-Personal information whenever you interact with our Website, such as the Internet domain address from which you reached our Website and analyze this data for trends and statistics. 

We receive and may store certain Personally Identifiable Information that you enter when visiting our website or that you provide to us in other ways. For instance, we collect the information you provide to us when you buy our products, use our services, send an email or call us, or respond to online surveys. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card information. This information may also include private information for your student athletes including their name, address, telephone number, email address, financial aid information, birth date, gender, and eligibility information. For marketing purposes, we may also ask about your personal interests, and other similar personal or preference data that you provide to us. You may also submit such information about other people such as the name and address of someone you are referring to us. Whether or not you provide such information to us is completely your own choice.

How We Use Your Information  
We use your Personally Identifiable Information you provide for our internal purposes, such as providing products and services to you, contacting you with regards to your use of our products and services, analyzing trends and statistics, informing you about our/our affiliate’s new products, services and offers, and providing you with information from and about our affiliates.

We work with affiliates that we believe are trustworthy and we require them to protect your information just as we do. These affiliates help us with many things, including helping provide products and services to you. We limit the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information with such affiliates to the extent necessary to provide you with the products and services you expect from us. Except when to do so would effectively disable our ability to provide products and services to you, we will not share your information with these affiliates if you have requested that we stop doing so.

To serve you better, we may combine the information you give us online or through printed forms; publicly available information; and information we receive from others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and services that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

Also, we may contract with third-party service providers to provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management, or promotional services. We provide the information needed for these service providers to perform these services. The information we provide may include some of your Personally Identifiable Information. However, these service providers are not authorized to use any of the information we share with them for any purposes other than to provide services to us.

We may share information that we have collected with governmental agencies and other organizations assisting us in fraud prevention or for investigative purposes. We may do so when permitted or mandated by law; trying to protect against or prevent fraud; attempting to prevent unauthorized or improper transactions; or investigating fraud or improper conduct that has already taken place. In these instances, the information is not provided to these agencies or organizations for marketing or any other unrelated purposes.

From time to time we may also market certain third-party services through our Website. Should you choose to accept an offer from a third-party, we will pass your relevant Personally Identifiable Information, including your name, postal address, credit/debit card number and any other required billing information to that specific third-party.

Finally, if some or all of the business assets of our company are sold or transferred, we would transfer any corresponding Non-Personal and Personally Identifiable Information to the purchaser so they could continue to provide you with products and services. We may also retain a copy of that information.

Changes to Your Information  
You may update your registered Personally Identifiable Information at any time. This includes your name, password, email, and postal address. You may also manage your mailing preferences and email formats.

If at any time you would like us to update your Personally Identifiable Information or remove you from our email or postal mailing lists, or if you need assistance with the modification of your information, send us an email with your request.

Opting Out of Sharing Information  
You may opt out of future unaffiliated third-party disclosures of your information. Such opt-out will not affect disclosures otherwise permitted by law including but not limited to: (i) disclosures to affiliates, (ii) disclosures to third-party service providers who provide certain services for our business, such as credit card processing, computer system services, shipping, data management, or promotional services, (iii) disclosures to third parties as necessary to fulfill your requests, (iv) disclosures to governmental agencies or law enforcement departments or otherwise required to be made under applicable law, (v) previously completed disclosures to third parties, or (vi) disclosures to third parties in connection with subsequent contests or promotions you may choose to enter, or third-party offers you may choose to accept.

Protecting the Privacy of Children  
Our Website is not designed for use by anyone under the age of 13 (Child). We do not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from a Child. You acknowledge that we cannot accurately verify the age of our Users nor do we have any liability to do so. If you are parent or legal guardian who suspects their Child is attempting to use our Website, please contact us immediately to remove your Child’s information. We will ask you to provide identification to confirm that you are indeed the Child’s parent or legal guardian. If you are under 18, please get your parent or legal guardian’s permission before attempting to use our Website. 

Our Email Policy  
Our affiliates and we fully comply with the federal CAN-SPAM Act. You can always opt out of receipt of further email correspondence from us. We will not sell, rent, or trade your email address to any unaffiliated third-party without your permission. We believe that your email address is personal and should be kept that way. We use your email address to provide better customer service, to facilitate your transactions with our third-party marketing partners, and to be able to inform you of the Internet offers and promotions from us or our affiliates.

Our Security Policy  
Because we all benefit from secure online transactions, we have taken steps to build and manage a system that you can use with confidence. We use sophisticated encryption and authentication tools to protect the security of the Personally Identifiable Information that you share with us. If sensitive data is collected through this Website, we will encrypt your Personally Identifiable Information before it travels over the Internet using industry standards for secure online transactions. The Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us is preserved behind a firewall, instead of being directly connected to the Internet. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Once we receive your transmission, we have appropriate security measures in place within our physical facilities to protect against the theft, loss, misuse, or alteration of the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided to us.

We urge you to keep your password for our Website in a safe place and not divulge it to anyone. Also remember to sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our Website. This is to ensure that others cannot access your account, especially if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place such as a library or Internet cafe.

Use of Credit Cards  
You may have to provide a credit card to purchase other products and services from our Website. We use third-party billing services and HAVE NO CONTROL over these services. We will use our best efforts to make sure that your credit card number is kept STRICTLY CONFIDENTIAL by using only third-party billing services that use industry-standard encryption technology to protect your credit card number from unauthorized use. If you note any irregularities on your credit card with regards to purchases made from JumpForward, please contact us immediately. We will use our best efforts to work with you and the appropriate authorities to resolve the matter. 

Cookies  
Our Website may send a “cookie” to your computer. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Cookies do not damage your system. We use cookies to identify which areas of our site you have visited, so the next time you visit the site, we can better personalize the content that you see on our Website. Most browser software can be set to reject Cookies. However, if you reject our Cookies, certain functionality on our Website may not work correctly or at all. We do not place Personally Identifiable Information in Cookies.

Web Beacons  
We may also use web beacons to collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our Website and the Websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by Web Beacons (a) allows us to statistically monitor how many people open our emails and (b) for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our Web Beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our Websites or those of our sponsors’. We do not link Non-Personal Information from Web Beacons to Personally Identifiable Information without your permission.

Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
From time to time, our privacy and security practices may change. If we modify our Privacy Policy, in whole or in part, to address these changes, we will indicate when such changes are made by changing the “Last Updated” date at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Those changes will be effective as of the Last Updated date. The new policy will apply to all current and past users of our Websites and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. We may change or add to this Privacy Policy, so we encourage you to review it periodically.

Questions About Our Privacy Policy  
To help us improve our privacy and security policies and practices, please send us your questions and feedback using the Contact Us and Feedback forms on our Website.
